blocksi.net 2019-04-11

# Privacy policy

When you use Blocksi services, you trust us with your information. This Privacy Policy is meant to help you understand what data we collect, why we collect it, and what we do with it. This is important; we hope you will take time to read it carefully. 

At Blocksi ("Service") we take privacy and the security of your data very seriously, so we'd like to be transparent with you about how we collect, utilize and protect it.

A lot of what you'll read in this document is designed to address various laws and regulations such as the [GDPR.](https://www.eugdpr.org/) or [California Student Data Privacy Agreeement (CSDPA)](https://secure2.cpsd.us/cspa/agreements/CSDPA_Final_V1_Overview_022717.pdf) That said, we'd like to take a moment to share a few philosophies that guide how we treat data and privacy here at Blocksi now and going forward:

* Data you provide us, or that is collected on your behalf, is owned entirely by you and will be available to you on demand as well as removed on demand.
* We consider data a liability and only collect and share the minimum amount required to provide you with a great service.

We've made an effort to make this document as clear and easy to understand as we can, but if you have any questions, please don't hesitate to reach out at **privacy@blocksi.net**.

_If you do not agree with this policy, please do not access or use our Service._

Who this policy applies to

* Our Customers who have signed up for our Service
* End-Users of our Customers who interact with our Service

## Privacy policy

There are many different ways you can use Blocksi Manager for Cloud Filtering and Classroom Management services –Either by using the Administrator dashboard, the Parent dashboard or the Teacher dashboard. As you use our services, we want you to be clear how we’re using information and the ways in which you can protect your privacy.

Our Privacy Policy explains:

* What information we collect and why we collect it.
* How we use that information.

We’ve tried to keep it as simple as possible, but if you’re not familiar with terms like, IP addresses, Hostname, URL and browsers, then read about these key terms first. Your privacy matters to Blocksi so whether you are new to Blocksi or a long-time user, please do take the time to get to know our practices – and if you have any questions contact us (privacy@blocksi.net). 

## Information we collect

We collect information to provide a cloud based internet and youtube filtering service for any GSuite Education user that has authenticated himself by logging into his google account whether on a desktop machine or a chromebook. 

### Information you give us.

As an Administrator , many of our services require you to sign up for a Blocksi Manager Education Everywhere Account either on the Administrator or on the teacher dashboard or on the portal dashboard. When you do, we’ll ask for personal information, like your name, email address, telephone number. As a student, you need to sign up for a Google account (GSuite Education) and we will collect then your email address and the Blocksi extension will then be enforced onto your chrome browser or chromebook. As a teacher, you need as well to sign up for a Google account to be able to use the Chromebook Classroom Management System (Teacher Dashboard) 

### Information we get from the student when Blocksi extension is enabled on his GSuite account

We collect information about the websites, every student visit or has attempted to visit, or has been denied access to , about youtube videos that have been watched or currently being watched . 

This information includes:

* **[Device](https://blocksi.net/key-terms.php#key05) information**
* We collect device-specific information (such as your hardware model, operating system version, [unique device identifiers.](https://blocksi.net/key-terms.php#key15) Blocksi may associate your device identifiers with your Google Account.
* **Log information**
* When students view internet content on Blocksi enabled chrome client, we automatically collect and store certain information in [server logs.](https://blocksi.net/key-terms.php#key14) This includes:

  * Details of the students search queries.
  * User google email address

* **Location information**
* When you use Blocksi services, we may collect and process information about your actual location. We use various technologies to determine location, including IP address, GPS, and other sensors that may, for example, provide Blocksi with information on nearby devices,Wi-Fi access points and cell towers.
* **Local storage**
* We may collect and store information (including personal information) locally on your device using mechanisms such as [browser web storage](https://blocksi.net/key-terms.php#key03) (including HTML 5) and [application data caches.](https://blocksi.net/key-terms.php#key02)

Information we collect, when a student is signed into a Blocksi enabled GSuite Education account , is associated with the student Google Account. When information is associated with your Google Account, we treat it as personal information. 

### How we use information we collect

* In Blocksi Manager Analytics and Insights Admin and Teacher Dashboard
* These services are provided to a school under its Blocksi for Education agreement and, as applicable, Data Processing Amendment. (Users and parents can ask their school if it has accepted the Data Processing Amendment.) 
* Blocksi does not serve ads nor use personal information collected for advertising purposes.
* The Blocksi Privacy Policy describes fully how Blocksi services generally use information. To summarize, we use the information we collect from all of our services to provide, maintain, protect and improve them, to develop new ones, and to protect Blocksi and our users. We also use this information to offer users tailored content, such as more relevant search results. We may combine personal information from one service with information, including personal information, from other Google services.
* For Blocksi Apps for Education users in primary and secondary (K-12) schools, Blocksi does not use any user personal information (or any information associated with an GSuite Apps for Education Account) to target ads, while using an Apps for Education account.

Blocksi processes personal information on our servers in many countries around the world. We may process your personal information on a server located outside the country where you live.

## Information you share

When a student GSuite account is enabled for Blocksi services, Blocksi only collects analytics related to the internet browsing activity of the student and whether he has been denied access to some category of internet content or some specific sites. Teacher dashboard allows to monitor students screen during the class. Our services provide you with different options on sharing and removing your content. 

## Accessing and updating your personal information

Whenever a student filtering is enforced by Blocksi, we aim to provide parents and guardian with access to their children web analytics and insights through the Parent Dashboard. If that information is wrong, we strive to give you ways to update it quickly or to delete it – unless we have to keep that information for legitimate business or legal purposes. When a parent request to update its children information, we may ask them to verify their identity before we can act on your request. To note that emancipated student or student aged above 18 years of age, are entitled to sign up for a Parent dashboard account and access their data with the same privileges (update or delete) as a regular parent or guardian. We may ask them to verify their identity before we can act on their request.

We may reject requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort (for example, developing a new system or fundamentally changing an existing practice), risk the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup systems).

Where we can provide information access and correction, we will do so for free, except where it would require a disproportionate effort. We aim to maintain our services in a manner that protects information from accidental or malicious destruction. Blocksi will delete such data from its systems as soon as reasonably practicable within a maximum period of 180 days, unless applicable legislation or legal process prevents it from doing so. For more information please refer to section 7 of our [Data Processing amendment ](https://blocksi.net/data-amendment.php)

### Transparency and choice

We provide a variety of user controls that enable Blocksi Manager For Education users (administrator and guardians) to make meaningful choices about how long information is stored in Blocksi services. Depending on the settings enabled by the school, users can use the various controls described in the Privacy Policy, such as Blocksi activity controls, to manage their privacy and information. We provide additional information for parents, students, and administrators on the Blocksi Manager for Education Privacy Center.

### Parental review and deletion of information

The parents of Blocksi Manager For Education users in Primary/Secondary (K-12) schools can access their child’s personal information from the Parent Dashboard and request that it be deleted through their dashboard. School administrators can provide for parental access and deletion of personal information consistent with the functionality of our services. If a parent wishes to stop any further collection or use of the child's information, the parent can request that the administrator use the service controls available to them to limit the child’s access to features or services, or delete the child’s account entirely. Guidance for administrators on how to use service controls to accomplish this is available in the [Help Center.](https://support.google.com/a)

## Information we share

We do not share personal information with companies, organizations and individuals outside of Blocksi unless one of the following circumstances applies:

* **With your consent**
* We will share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Blocksi when we have your consent to do so. We require opt-in consent for the sharing of any [sensitive personal information.](https://blocksi.net/key-terms.php#key13)
* **With domain administrators**
* If the Blocksi students analytics and filtering policies is managed for you by a [domain administrator](https://support.google.com/a/answer/178897?hl=en) (for example, for Google Apps users) then your domain administrator and resellers who provide user support to your organization will have access to your Blocksi Account information (including web and youtube analytics ). Your domain administrator may be able to:

  * view statistics regarding your account, like statistics which website you went to visit, were access denied and video you’ve watched, and when actually you logged in and used your chrome account or chromebook.
  * suspend or terminate your account access.
  * access or retain and print information stored as part of your account. 
  * receive your account information in order to satisfy applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request.
  * restrict your ability to delete or edit information or privacy settings.

* Please refer to your domain administrator’s privacy policy for more information.
* **For external processing**

We do not provide personal information to any [affiliates](https://blocksi.net/key-terms.php#key01) or other businesses or persons to process it for us. 

* **For legal reasons**
* We will share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Blocksi if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:

  * meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request.
  * enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations.
  * detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues.
  * protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Blocksi, our users or the public as required or permitted by law.

We may share [non-personally identifiable information](https://blocksi.net/key-terms.php#key09) publicly and with our partners – like publishers. For example, we may share information publicly to show trends about the general use of our services.

If Blocksi is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, we will continue to ensure the confidentiality of any personal information as per this policy and as per any privacy pledge Blocksi has made. We will give affected users notice before personal information is transferred or becomes subject to a different privacy policy which would have to comply at a minimum with all the requirements made under the current and latest updated Blocksi privacy policy.

## Information security

We work hard to protect Blocksi and our users from unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of information we hold. In particular:

* We encrypt many of our services using [SSL.](https://support.google.com/websearch/answer/173733?hl=en)
* We offer you two step verification when administrator, teacher or parent or guardian access your student Blocksi analytics and insights Account.
* We review our information collection, storage and processing practices, including physical security measures, to guard against unauthorized access to systems.
* We restrict access to personal information to Blocksi employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to process it for us, and who are subject to strict contractual confidentiality obligations and may be disciplined or terminated if they fail to meet these obligations.

## When this Privacy Policy applies

Our Privacy Policy applies to all of the services and products offered by Blocksi LLC but excludes services that have separate privacy policies that do not incorporate this Privacy Policy.

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to services offered by other companies or individuals. Our Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of other companies and organizations who may be using our services through API (Application Programming Interface) we may provide in the future.

## Usage implies consent

By using Blocksi Manager Education Everywhere (Administrator, Parent and Teacher Dashboard) , you consent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use Blocksi Manager.

## Compliance and cooperation with regulatory authorities

We regularly review our compliance with our Privacy Policy. We also adhere to several self regulatory frameworks, including the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework. When we receive formal written complaints, we will contact the person who made the complaint to follow up. We work with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that we cannot resolve with our users directly.

## Changes

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without the administrator and guardian explicit consent. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page. We will post it as well on a one-time dialog box you will be presented to, the first time you login to any Blocksi services, after these changes have been implemented. Explicit Consent (“I agree”) will be required to further use Blocksi services. We will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review.

## Additional limitations

Despite our best efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. In this regard, we are not responsible for events or conditions beyond our reasonable control to the extent that they relate to or impact the obligations assumed, or commitments made, hereunder. However, in the event of any data breach or other violation of this Privacy Policy caused by factors outside of our reasonable control, we will comply with all applicable laws in this regard, including those requiring notification in the event of certain defined data breaches.

## International users

As Blocksi LLC is a U.S.-based company, your personal information will likely be collected and maintained in the United States. If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may be different from U.S. law, then by using this Blocksi products, you consent to your personal information being collected, used and transferred as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

## Contact information

Blocksi LLC takes privacy issues very seriously. If you have any questions, suggestions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at privacy@blocksi.net

Blocksi LLC

ATTN: Privacy Officer

248 Hamilton avenue 3rd Floor

Palo Alto, CA 94303

Phone: 650-521-9976

Email: privacy@blocksi.net

URL: www.blocksi.net/PRIVACY

## We keep your student, children and staff personal information private and safe — and put you in control.

As you probably heard, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) took effect on May 25, 2018. GDPR has been designed to provide individuals with greater control over how their personal data is collected, stored, transferred, and used, while also simplifying the regulatory environment across the European Union (EU). This new regulation impacts both organizations that conduct business in the EU, as well as businesses that maintain or process EU personal data. LogMeIn recognizes the importance of the evolving legal and regulatory landscape around information security and data privacy and remains firmly committed to GDPR readiness by no later than the effective date.

Some key GDPR principles to consider in implementation include:

**Integrity:** Securing and safeguarding personal data using appropriate technical and organizational security measures.

**Lawfulness:** Organizations must, among other things, ensure they have a legal basis for processing personal data, and process that data in a fair and transparent manner.

**Limited Use:** Personal data may only be collected for specific, explicit, or legitimate purposes.

**Data Minimization:** Only collect data that is relevant and necessary for its intended use.

**Accuracy:** Personal data must be accurate and up-to-date.

**Storage Limitation:** Subject to relevant exceptions, maintain personal data only for as long as is deemed necessary and reasonable.

At Blocksi, accessible from https://www.blocksi.net/, one of our main priorities is the privacy of our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and recorded by Blocksi and how we use it.

If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us through email at tdraksler@block.si

## General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

We are a Data Controller of your information.

Blocksi legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Information we collect and the specific context in which we collect the information:

  * Blocksi needs to perform a contract with you
  * You have given Blocksi permission to do so
  * Processing your personal information is in Blocksi legitimate interests
  * Blocksi needs to comply with the law

Blocksi will retain your personal information only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our policies.

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. If you wish to be informed what Personal Information we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us. Our Privacy Policy was generated with the help of [GDPR Privacy Policy Generator](https://gdprprivacypolicy.net.com/) and the [GDPR Privacy Policy Template](https://privacy-policy-template.com/).

In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:

  * The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you.
  * The right of rectification.
  * The right to object.
  * The right of restriction.
  * The right to data portability
  * The right to withdraw consent

## Log Files

Blocksi follows a standard procedure of using log files. These files log visitors when they visit websites. All hosting companies do this and a part of hosting services' analytics. The information collected by log files include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date and time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. These are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. The purpose of the information is for analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movement on the website, and gathering demographic information.

## Privacy Policies

You may consult this list to find the Privacy Policy for each of the advertising partners of Blocksi.

Third-party ad servers or ad networks uses technologies like cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons that are used in their respective advertisements and links that appear on Blocksi, which are sent directly to users' browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. These technologies are used to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see on websites that you visit.

Note that Blocksi has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

## Third Pary Privacy Policies

Blocksi's Privacy Policy does not apply to other advertisers or websites. Thus, we are advising you to consult the respective Privacy Policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information. It may include their practices and instructions about how to opt-out of certain options. You may find a complete list of these Privacy Policies and their links here: Privacy Policy Links.

You can choose to disable cookies through your individual browser options. To know more detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers, it can be found at the browsers' respective websites. What Are Cookies?

## Children's Information

Another part of our priority is adding protection for children while using the internet. We encourage parents and guardians to observe, participate in, and/or monitor and guide their online activity.

Blocksi does not knowingly collect any Personal Identifiable Information from children under the age of 13. If you think that your child provided this kind of information on our website, we strongly encourage you to contact us immediately and we will do our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

## Online Privacy Policy Only

Our Privacy Policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website with regards to the information that they shared and/or collect in Blocksi. This policy is not applicable to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website.

## Consent

By using our website, you hereby consent to our Privacy Policy and agree to its terms.
